¬
{Author_1}Cornflower, at the Great Hall of Redwall
{Author_2}Cluny the Scourge, after running Scullface over with a cart
{Author_3}Abbot Mortimer, on his death bed
{Author_4}Martin the Warrior, in a vision
{Author_5}Matthias
{Author_6}Brother Methuselah
{Author_7}Jess and Friar Hugo
{Author_8}Martin the Warrior
{Quote_1}'Matthias, don’t be ashamed, I know why you cry and grieve. It is because you are kind and good not a hardhearted pitiless rat like Cluny.' 
{Quote_2}'Tell the Devil Cluny sent you, Scullface!' 
{Quote_3}'My old friend, I am not like the seasons. I cannot go on forever. It has to finish sometime.' 
{Quote_4}'There are very few such swords as this one left in the world, but remember, it is only a sword.'
{Quote_5}'All work and no play makes Matthias a dull mouse.' 
{Quote_6}'Knowledge is a thing that one cannot have enough of. It is the fruit of wisdom, to be eaten carefully and digested fully, unlike that lunch you are bolting down, little friend.' 
{Quote_7}- 'Tell me, Jess. What dreadful thing has happened?' - 'I fear that Cluny has tore up one of your oldest and most venerable dishrags. Alas, Redwall will never see it wipe another plate.' 
{Quote_8}'I am that is, my sword shall wield for me'
